<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi-objective Optimization | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/multi-objective-optimization/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/multi-objective-optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Multi-objective Optimization</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:16:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Multi-objective Optimization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/multi-objective-optimization/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danger is My Middle Lane: Simulations from Real-World Dangerous Roads</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ssbse-nier2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ssbse-nier2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test case prioritization techniques have emerged as effective strategies to optimize this process and mitigate the regression testing costs. Commonly, black-box heuristics guide optimal test ordering, leveraging information retrieval (e.g., cosine distance) to measure the test case distance and sort them accordingly. However, a challenge arises when dealing with tests of varying granularity levels, as they may employ distinct vocabularies (e.g., name identifiers). In this paper, we propose to measure the distance between test cases based on the shortest path between their identifiers within the WordNet lexical database. This additional heuristic is combined with the traditional cosine distance to prioritize test cases in a multi-objective fashion. Our preliminary study conducted with two different Java projects shows that test cases prioritized with WordNet achieve larger fault detection capability (APFD) compared to the traditional cosine distance used in the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective Black-Box Test Case Prioritization Based on Wordnet Distances</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ssbse-nier2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ssbse-nier2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test case prioritization techniques have emerged as effective strategies to optimize this process and mitigate the regression testing costs. Commonly, black-box heuristics guide optimal test ordering, leveraging information retrieval (e.g., cosine distance) to measure the test case distance and sort them accordingly. However, a challenge arises when dealing with tests of varying granularity levels, as they may employ distinct vocabularies (e.g., name identifiers). In this paper, we propose to measure the distance between test cases based on the shortest path between their identifiers within the WordNet lexical database. This additional heuristic is combined with the traditional cosine distance to prioritize test cases in a multi-objective fashion. Our preliminary study conducted with two different Java projects shows that test cases prioritized with WordNet achieve larger fault detection capability (APFD) compared to the traditional cosine distance used in the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fast Multi-objective Evolutionary Approach for Designing Large-Scale Optical Mode Sorter</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/gecco2023a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 10:56:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/gecco2023a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single and Multi-objective Test Cases Prioritization for Self-driving Cars in Virtual Environments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/acm-tosem2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:21:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/acm-tosem2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective Test Case Selection Through Linkage Learning-driven Crossover</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ssbse2021a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 09:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ssbse2021a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test case selection (TCS) aims to select a subset of the test suite to run for regression testing. The selection is typically based on past coverage and execution cost data. Researchers have successfully used multi-objective evolutionary algorithms (MOEAs), such as NSGA-II and its variants, to solve the problem. These MOEAs use traditional crossovers to create new candidate solutions during the search. Recent studies in evolutionary computation showed that more effective recombinations can be made by using linkage learning. Inspired by these recent advances in this field, we propose a new variant of NSGA-II, called L2-NSGA, that uses linkage learning to optimize test case selection. In particular, we use an unsupervised clustering algorithm to infer promising patterns among the solutions (sub-test suites). Then, these patterns are used in the next iterations of L2-NSGA to create solutions that contain/preserve these inferred patterns. Our results show that our customizations make NSGA-II more effective for test case selection. Furthermore, the test suite sub-sets generated by L2-NSGA are less expensive and more effective (detect more faults) than those generated by MOEAs used in the literature for regression testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Things Come In Threes: Improving Search-based Crash Reproduction With Helper Objectives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ase2020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 22:27:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ase2020a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-objective versus Multi-Objectivized Optimization for Evolutionary Crash Reproduction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ssbse2018a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:06:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ssbse2018a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defect Prediction as a Multi-Objective Optimization Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/stvr2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 23:50:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/stvr2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
