<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Empirical Software Engineering | Annibale Panichella</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/empirical-software-engineering/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/empirical-software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Empirical Software Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 19:37:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Empirical Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/empirical-software-engineering/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CATMA: Conformance Analysis Tool For Microservice Applications</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/icse2024-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 19:37:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/icse2024-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The microservice architecture allows developers to divide the core functionality of their software system into multiple smaller services. However, this architectural style also makes it harder for them to debug and assess whether the system&amp;rsquo;s deployment conforms to its implementation. We present CATMA, an automated tool that detects non-conformances between the system&amp;rsquo;s deployment and implementation. It automatically visualizes and generates potential interpretations for the detected discrepancies. Our evaluation of CATMA shows promising results in terms of performance and providing useful insights. CATMA is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cyber-analytics.nl/catma.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://cyber-analytics.nl/catma.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;, and a demonstration video is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/WKP1hG-TDKc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/WKP1hG-TDKc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slow and The Furious? Performance Antipattern Detection in Cyber-Physical Systems</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/jss2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 17:32:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/jss2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Silence: the Threats of Using LLMs in Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/icse-nier2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:29:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/icse-nier2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs) have gained considerable traction within the Software Engineering (SE) community, impacting various SE tasks from code completion to test generation, from program repair to code summarization. Despite their promise, researchers must still be careful as numerous intricate factors can influence the outcomes of experiments involving LLMs.
This paper initiates an open discussion on potential threats to the validity of LLM-based research including issues such as closed-source models, possible data leakage between LLM training data and research evaluation, and the reproducibility of LLM-based findings.
In response, this paper proposes a set of guidelines tailored for SE researchers and Language Model (LM) providers to mitigate these concerns.
The implications of the guidelines are illustrated using existing good practices followed by LLM providers and a practical example for SE researchers in the context of test case generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Delivery practices for Cyber- Physical systems: An interview-based study</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/acm-tosem2022b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:21:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/acm-tosem2022b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Kill Them All: An Exploratory Study on the Impact of Code Observability on Mutation Testing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/jss2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:32:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/jss2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Testing in The IDE: Patterns, Beliefs, And Behavior</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ieee-tse2018c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 11:24:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ieee-tse2018c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Catch &#39;Em All: WatchDog, a Family of IDE Plug-Ins to Assess Testing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/serip2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 07:54:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/serip2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery Practices in a Large Financial Organization</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/icsme2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 07:51:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/icsme2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of test case summaries on bug fixing performance: An empirical investigation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/icse2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 07:43:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/icse2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labeling Source Code with Information Retrieval Methods: An Empirical Study.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/emse2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 23:52:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/emse2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
