<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Annibale Panichella</title>
    <link>https://apanichella.github.io/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Annibale Panichella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 10:29:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apanichella.github.io/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Search-Based-LDA</title>
      <link>https://apanichella.github.io/tools/ssbse-lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 10:29:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apanichella.github.io/tools/ssbse-lda/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Comparison of Search Algorithms for Topic Modelling - A Study on Duplicate Bug Report Identification
Author Annibale Panichella
Venue SSBSE 2019
Abstract Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) has been used to support many software engineering tasks. Previous studies showed that default settings lead to sub-optimal topic modeling with a dramatic impact on the performance of such approaches in terms of precision and recall. For this reason, researchers used search algorithms (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGE-MOEA</title>
      <link>https://apanichella.github.io/tools/age-moea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 11:08:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apanichella.github.io/tools/age-moea/</guid>
      <description>Title An Adaptive Evolutionary Algorithm based on Non-Euclidean Geometry for Many-objective Optimization
Author Annibale Panichella
Venue GECCO 2019
Abstract In the last decade, several evolutionary algorithms have been proposed in the literature for solving multi- and many-objective optimization problems. The performance of such algorithms depends on their capability to produce a well-diversified front (diversity) that is as closer to the Pareto optimal front as possible (proximity). Diversity and proximity strongly depend on the geometry of the Pareto front, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>